so we did a video about the web and
somebody made the comment that they took
what I was saying to mean the internet
and so I want to clarify the internet
and the web are not the same thing um
the interwebs right the internet without
getting deep into that we will get into
it in another video about what
networking is and how it works the
internet is a method of connecting
computers generally and the worldwide
web is a spefic specific usage of those
connected
computers um just like email just like
streaming just like IRC messaging uh
gaming gaming you know uses the internet
so you know it's fair to say that
Minecraft which is having an anniversary
coming up is a internet technology it
can be played over the internet but the
M Minecraft doesn't have anything to do
with the worldwide web at all right so
the web uses the internet uh as a method
of communicating and there were many
other similar Technologies when the web
came out such as gopher uh well at least
one other technology that tried to do
the same thing right that collaborative
way of storing uh uh data documents in
particular and allowing them to be
shared um so there have been other
approaches in the past I've actually
tried to invent something called a
knowledge exchange grid which is was I'm
I'm not going to do that anymore but it
would be an attempt to make a better
worldwide web that's not so cluttered
with all the different things that are
in it um which create problems today so
the web is not the web requires the
internet but the web is not the internet
they are not synonyms okay